<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redmond Python</title>
    <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Redmond Python</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This workshop was initially created by [Philly&#39;s Python User Group](http://phillypythonworkshop.github.io/) and adapted by the [Redmond Python User Group](https://www.meetup.com/Redmond-Python-User-Group/).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 15:59:39 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.redmondpython.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First Redmond Python User Group Meetup</title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/first-redmond-python-user-group-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 15:59:39 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/first-redmond-python-user-group-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On February 6 we&amp;rsquo;ll be having the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Redmond-Python-User-Group/&#34;&gt;first meeting&lt;/a&gt; for the Redmond Python user group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For anyone joining us, here&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;ll be doing!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/dictionaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/dictionaries/</guid>
      <description> Title Schedule Overview Basic Syntax &amp;amp; Rules Utility Functions Example 1 Example 2 Example 3 Review of Key Points Exercises </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/functions/</guid>
      <description> Title Schedule Overview Basic Syntax &amp;amp; Rules Utility Functions Example 1 Example 2 Example 3 Review of Key Points Exercises </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/intro/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Python Schedule  Overview Python Features Installation Using the Interpreter Tracebacks Comments Review Exercises Additional Resources  Overview Python is an easy-to-write, easy-to-read interpreted scripting language. &amp;ldquo;Hello world!&amp;rdquo; looks like this:
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;print(&amp;quot;Hello world!&amp;quot;) Hello world!  Here&amp;rsquo;s a more complex example (an application to send an email).
 Import some code. Create an SMTP object to connect with a server. Log in to the server. Create our message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/lecture_template/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/lecture_template/</guid>
      <description>Title Schedule A bulleted list of the things that you will cover in this lecture.
Overview high-level statements about the topic, what it&amp;rsquo;s used for, and its significance.
Basic Syntax &amp;amp; Rules include lots of examples of DOs and DO NOTs, as well as any gotchas
Utility Functions any built-in utility functions that devs might find helpful
Example 1 a few small/mid/large examples showing how the concept is implemented</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/lists/</guid>
      <description> Title Schedule Overview Basic Syntax &amp;amp; Rules Utility Functions Example 1 Example 2 Example 3 Review of Key Points Exercises </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/loops/</guid>
      <description> Title Schedule Overview Basic Syntax &amp;amp; Rules Utility Functions Example 1 Example 2 Example 3 Review of Key Points Exercises </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/numbers_operators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/numbers_operators/</guid>
      <description>Numbers and Operators Schedule  Overview Basic Syntax &amp;amp; Rules Math Operators Utility Functions Examples Review Exercises Additional Resources  Overview Number data types store numeric values. They are immutable data types, means that changing the value of a number data type results in a new object.
Basic Syntax &amp;amp; Rules There are two numerical types that we will learn about:
 integers: Positive or negative whole numbers with no decimal point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/strings/</guid>
      <description> Title Schedule Overview Basic Syntax &amp;amp; Rules quotes Utility Functions Example 1 Example 2 Example 3 Review of Key Points Exercises </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/tuples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/lectures/tuples/</guid>
      <description> Title Overview Basic Syntax &amp;amp; Rules Utility Functions Example 1 Example 2 Example 3 Review of Key Points Exercises </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to Redmondpython.com</title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/contributing/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick guide on how you can contribute to Redmondpython.com
 For help with github commands and repository management, here is a quick guide
 You can also check out GitKraken - a client for Git
  The Repo
The repository is available here
Requirements
You would need Hugo and additionaly HomeBrew if you are on the macOS
Running the local instance
Running the instance locally is a simple</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day One Lesson</title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/day_one_lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/day_one_lesson/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Day One! This is the self-guided, self-paced tutorial for day 1. We&amp;rsquo;ve included a break in the middle, but remember to take a break to stretch, get some water, or take a moment to relax any time you need to. If at any time you have questions, ask away!
If you&amp;rsquo;ve not yet done so, ensure you&amp;rsquo;ve gone through these setup instructions to install and configure Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Two Lesson</title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/day_two_lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/day_two_lesson/</guid>
      <description>Lecture outline Review Day 1 material  math type() variables strings booleans if/elif/else functions  lists  purpose initialization len() review accessing elements adding elements changing elements slicing lists  tuples  like lists but immutable can perform all the same operations except changing elements strings are like tuples - can slice, access elements, can not change elements  loops and more flow control  for loops if statements inside for loops nested for loops range() while loops infinite loops if statements inside while loops break input()  dictionaries  purpose initialization accessing elements adding elements changing elements keys() and values()  modules  purpose builtins imports  math  math.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/setup/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;ll do to get yourself ready to work on Python basics and projects.
Choose your operating system:
 Linux MacOS Windows  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Exercises</title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/practice/</guid>
      <description>Here are some tutorials and exercises to practice your new Python skills.
Exercises and tutorials in Python 3 Interactive Python This includes some theory as well as some practical exercises.
Python Tutorial from University of Waterloo Follow the tutorial and run interactive code in your browser.
Exercises and tutorials in Python 2 These exercises and tutorials are in Python 2, but since they&amp;rsquo;re all browser-based you should be able to follow along regardless of what version of Python you use locally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Download these projects as part of the workshop curriculum.
Sparrow
Build a Twitter bot that Tweets things out for you, you can even deploy it to an Infrastructure as a Service provider like AWS. Here is a comprehensive walkthrough.
Wordplay
Explore these short Python files that help you cheat at Scrabble or crossword puzzles. Wordplay is comptatible with both Python 2 &amp;amp; Python 3. Git clone or download zip file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup - Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/setuplinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/setuplinux/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to do to set up your Linux machine.
Download and Install Python Most Linux machines have both Python 2 and Python 3 pre-installed. Open a Terminal window and type python3 at the prompt. You should see something like the example in the Python shell section below. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, please see an instructor.
Prepare a text editor While you can absolutely write python code in any text editor, it is a lot easier to use one that is aware of code content and provides relevant features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup - Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/setupmac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/setupmac/</guid>
      <description>While Macs come with Python 2.7.x pre-installed, but because Python 2&amp;rsquo;s end-of-life is just around the corner, we&amp;rsquo;ll be working with Python 3 during this session so there&amp;rsquo;s some light installation ahead of us. This will require administrative priveleges on your computer since the Python installation is usually done to protected directories. Along the way, we&amp;rsquo;ll also set up a more advanced text editor that will help us by providing some really specific programming features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup - Windows</title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/setupwindows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/setupwindows/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to do to set up your Windows machine.
Download and Install Python If you already think you have Python 3 installed, please check with a staff member before completing these instructions.
 Click on this download link and choose &amp;ldquo;run&amp;rdquo; if you have the option to do so. Otherwise, save it to your computer and double click to start the installer.
 Windows may prompt you on whether you want to run or install Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Checkoff</title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/setupcheckoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/setupcheckoff/</guid>
      <description>When you&amp;rsquo;re ready, let an instructor or assistant know. Together you will go through the following check off steps:
 Start a new command prompt, and from that command prompt start Python 3. Then quit Python 3. Create a new Python file (with a .py extension). In that file, type the following and save the file. From a command prompt, navigate to this file and execute that Python script.
print(&amp;quot;Hello world!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Workshop</title>
      <link>https://www.redmondpython.com/short_workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.redmondpython.com/short_workshop/</guid>
      <description>This workshop guide is meant to be used when we&amp;rsquo;ve only got an hour or two to start learning Python. Keep in mind, you&amp;rsquo;re not going to be able to learn everything in an hour! But hopefully this will get you pointed in the right direction. Now, because the maintainers of Python 2 will stop supporting it in 2020 you probably want to learn Python 3. This all assumes you&amp;rsquo;ll be using Python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>